So, for the last two questions regarding
对于前面的两个问题
the relationships of the other variables with salary and job satisfaction,
与工资和工作满意度相关的因素有哪些
we'll probably want to build some sort of predictive model.
我们可能需要构建某种预测模型
So we read in the data set and did
所以我们先读取数据
this.describe to get just a basic summary of a lot of the aspects of the data.
使用 describe 来获取数据的统计信息
And then, this first question is about matching
第一个问题是
these values to their description down below based on sort of what we can see up here.
将下面的这些值和陈述匹配
So, a column just listing an index for each row,
第一个陈述 "只是列出了每行数据索引的列"
that's the respondent column.
这应该是指 Respondent 这一列
So it's just a number if you were to look at that in the header.
我们可以在前面的数据里看到
So, if you look at that in the header you can see respondents just one, two, three, four,
这里的 1 2 3 4 5
five and it continues that numbering if you were to look at it further down.
其实就是索引
The maximum satisfaction on the scales for the survey, the maximum satisfaction.
下一个 "满意度的最高评分是多少"
So, there are multiple things related to satisfaction.
其实有多个特征都跟满意度相关
So, there's job, and career,
工作满意度、职业满意度以及
and stack overflow, and the maximum for that is 10.
对 Stack Overflow 的满意度 最大值是 10
So the maximum satisfaction on each of these scales for
对每种满意度来说 最大值都是 10
the survey is 10 or e. The column with the most missing values,
这里就是 e 选项 接下来是缺失值最多的列
so we can actually see this from the count up here.
我们可以从上面 count 这一行里看到
So the one with the smallest count is the one with the most missing values.
count 值最小的 就意味着包含最多的缺失值
So that would be the expected salary
所以就是 ExpectedSalary
has the most missing values and then the variable with the highest spread of values.
拥有最多的缺失值 下一个 离散程度最高的列
The highest spread means that it has
离散程度最高意味着其拥有
the largest standard deviation or the largest distance between the max and the min,
最大的标准偏差 或最大值和最小值之间的差距最大
that's another way we could do it.
这是另一种对比方式
I'm just going to look at the standard deviations and you can see here,
我打算只对比标准偏差
40,753, it looks like salary has the highest spread.
可以看到 40753 最大 所以工资的离散程度是最大的
Sometimes, a picture can tell us more so we can run this list.
有时 图表能展示更多信息 运行这个 hist
You can see that career satisfaction is left skewed,
你可以看到 职业满意度是左偏的
and job satisfaction is left skewed,
工作满意度也是左偏的
salaries right skewed, hours per week is right skewed,
工资是右偏的 周工作时长是右偏的
stack overflow satisfaction is left skewed,
对 Stack Overflow 的满意度也是左偏的
expected salaries kind of right skewed,
期望工资好像有点右偏
and the respondents really even because there's just one of
而 Respondent 这个变量则是均匀分布的
them for every single individual, okay.
因为每个答卷者都具有唯一的编号
And then, there's also this really nice picture called the heatmap.
这里还有一个非常漂亮的图 — 热图
In general, here you can see that the darker ones are closer to zero.
总的来说 颜色越深的地方值就越接近于零
So, all the dark squares here sort of
基本上深色的正方形
suggests that there's not high correlations between certain things.
说明两个变量之间没有很大的相关性
So, this is like the correlation between expected salary and
比如说 这里的期望工资和答卷者编号之间的相关性很弱
anything with the respondent number to be very high.
符合我们的预期
But you can see this one between job satisfaction and career satisfaction as the highest.
工作满意度和职业满意度的相关性是最强的
Anything off of the diagonal basically,
可以看到对角线右上方的内容
anything in this top right is essentially the same as the bottom
与左下方基本上是完全相同的
left so you only have to look at half of this to get the information.
只需要观察其中之一即可
Yeah. Not a lot of high correlations and you can see that there are some missing points.
这里并没有很多强的相关性 还可以看到有些地方是缺失的
So, if someone marked a career satisfaction they didn't mark an expected salary.
如果某人给出职业满意度 但是并没有给出期望工资
If someone marked a job satisfaction they didn't mark an expected salary.
或者给出了工作满意度但没有给出期望工资
And if somebody marked a salary they didn't mark an expected salary.
或者给出了工资但没有给出期望工资
So there's a number of things where there's missing data if.
这样就会有很多缺失值
If you don't have an expected salary then you have these three things.
还有一种情况就是给出了期望工资 但没有给出其他三项
If you have one of these three things it doesn't look like you have an expected salary,
或者反过来
there's no overlap there.
那交叉部分就没办法计算了
So, the column with the strongest correlation with salary, let's see here.
这个问题是 哪个特征与工资的相关性最强
So, here is salary.
这里是工资
The one with the highest correlation looks like this 0.15 which is career satisfaction.
相关系数最大的似乎是与职业满意度的 0.15
So I'm going to mark this
所以这里选 f
as f. The data suggests more hours work relates to higher salary,
下一个 工作时长越高工资也越高
I'm going to mark that as a,
我会选 No
no, because if we look at things associated with salary none of them are very high,
因为跟工资相关的特征 没有哪个是很高的
hours per week is actually negatively related, so there's that.
甚至工作时长跟工资反而是负相关的
Data in the blank column meant missing data and two other columns.
哪个特征缺少两个与其他列的相关系数
So, actually, three other columns,
实际上 应该三列都缺失
but I'm going mark c. Yes.
这里我选 c
So, if you had a missing data and expected salary column,
这在图里的最后一行可以看到
then there was missing data in actually three other columns but also two other columns.
期望工资和其他三个特征之间没有值 也就是缺失的
And then, the strongest negative relationship had what correlation?
最强负相关的相关系数是多少?
So, I see a negative 0.15 that looks like the lowest.
这里有一个 -0.15 看上去好像是最小值
So, the lowest one they have is negative 0.12 but I think it should be negative 0.15.
但是这里写的是 -0.12
So, I'll get that changed as well.
应该要改一下
Catching all of the errors in this video.
在这里填上 g
Cool. So that looks great.
看上去不错
The next part was to fit our model.
下一步是拟合模型
So, we subset our data to only the quantitative variables,
先筛选出数值变量
and then, we were trying to predict salary.
想要预测的是 Salary
We split this into the training and
把数据划分为训练集和测试集
test set and then there's basically four steps that we wanted to do.
主要有四个步骤
So, we fit our linear model,
我们拟合线性模型
so we instantiate our model,
先实例化模型
and then we try to fit it,
然后尝试拟合
and when we do all of this you can see it breaks.
运行这些代码 你会看到出现了报错
And so, using results above to match each variable as the appropriate key in to this.
下个问题 将下面的字母变量名匹配到对应的表述中
So, what is the reason that the fit method broke?
第一个 上面代码报错的原因是什么
And the reason it broke is because we have missing values in the X matrix.
报错的原因是 X 矩阵里有缺失值
So, asking learn fit methods cannot accept none values.
也就是说 sklearn 的 fit 方法不能接受缺失值
That's d. What does the random state parameter do for the training test split?
也就是 d 下个问题 train_test_split 里的 random_state 参数有什么用
So, what it does is it makes sure that if multiple people run this code,
其作用是 确保不同的人运行这段代码
we all get the same training and test sets.
都能获得相同的训练集和测试集
So, it assures the train and test split will occur,
对照一下这些内容 它能确保
the same train and test split will occur for multiple users.
对不同的用户产生相同的测试集和训练集
So b, and what is the purpose of creating a train test split?
也就是 b 下个问题 划分训练集和测试集的目的是什么?
And the purpose of creating the train to split is to make sure that
目的是为了确保模型
your model extends well to new situations.
能够拥有较好的扩展性
So, not only does it fit well on the data that it sought to
也就是说 不仅要在训练集上表现良好
train but it extends well to testing data or data it hasn't seen before.
在测试集上 以及没有见过的数据集上 也能有比较好的表现
So, I'm going to say, a.
所以应该是选 a
And it looks great.
看上去很棒
So, it's like we're ready for the next thing.
准备学习下一部分的内容